Dharaneesh Anthikapalli

■ dharaneeshoffl2001@gmail.com

7383849310

12/07/2001

Indian

in linkedin.com/in/dharaneesh-anthikapalli-4531b1194

github.com/Dharaneesho9

9 39-33-15/12/6 Vuda Colony, Madhavadhara, 530018 Visakhapatnam, Andhra Pradesh, India

Professional Summary

Seeking a fresher's role to improve and utilize my technical knowledge gained at VIT University in the last three years. I'm presently pursuing my Bachelor's degree in Computer Science, and I have scored really well. I have done other internships and projects that have quite helpful technical solutions for modern-day problems.

Education

2019 – 2023 **Vellure Institute of Technology, Chennai,**

Tamilnadu, India Bachler of Technology, Computer Science with Cyber Physical Systems

present CGPA is 9.23

2017 – 2019 Sri Chaitanya Educational Institutions, Hyderabad, 12th

Telangana, India Passed out with a score of 97.3%

2017 Shri Swaminarayan Gurukul International School, Medak, CBSE

Telangana, India Passed out with 10 CGPA

Professional Experience

06/2021 - 07/2021

07/2021 – 09/2021 **Tecogno Solutions,** Software Developer Intern

• Developed a 3D model which scales itself to resemble a person's body

• Created programs that can read the information from the forms of old times and makes csv files out of them for digitalisation of past data

The Sparks Foundation, Data Science and Business Analytics Intern

• Made Decision Tree Classifier Model

07/2020 - present HackClub VIT, Chennai, Blackbox automator

a community of enthusiastic people, good at various trending technologies

07/2019 – present **PALS VIT, Chennai,** Student Event Manager

• Demonstrated respect, friendliness, and willingness to help whenever needed

• Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions

Projects

08/2021 - 12/2021 **A**

Analysis of Impact of Water Quality on Crop Production

This is a data analysis work, where we analyzed the effects that chemicals in water at different states had on the crops they produced, done using RStudio

https://github.com/Dharaneesho9/Impact-of-water-on-crop-production-using-R

08/2021 - 12/2021

Context Aware Smart Bus

This program is capable of making a bus, aware of the environment around it and what happened in the past and could take intelligent decisions to get the best out of the situation, assuming that it is provided with required hardware

https://github.com/Dharaneesho9/Context-Aware-SmartBus-Java

01/2021 - 04/2021

3D User Manual Using Unity

In the project, we create an application that is capable of elucidating your products at the next level, so basically, the application is capable of explaining your product in the 3D space virtually through your phone, where you exactly know what your manual is trying to explain about

01/2021 - 03/2021

Target Spotter using PSO and OpenCV

it uses an AI-based computing technique, i.e Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO). An image processing technique is used to find the features of the image which is the ORB algorithm, then KNN algorithm for matching them, and Operating system related multiprocessing techniques are used for enabling parallel computing for faster computation. All these techniques are integrated together to get the task done.

https://github.com/Dharaneesho9/Target-spotter-Using-PSO-and-OpenCV

08/2020 - 12/2020

Traffic Surveillance Using OpenCV and Python,

Serves more like a target finder ♂

It's a software application that helps the police and traffic services to keep a check on vehicles that are found to be hazardous

Skills

Python(mainly sklearn, Flask, bpy,cv2)

C++

JAVA

Git and GitHub

Simulink

Matlab

Used for Controller design

Ptolemy

Arduino

Micro Controller

SQL

HTML, CSS and Javascript

also worked with C#, Neo4j, Blender as part of my other projects and internships

Languages

• English

• Hindi

• Telugu